thefordstory.com 2013-12-21

# Ford Social: Privacy Policy

**The Effective Date of this Privacy Statement is May 1, 2013**

**Privacy Policy**

**Our Privacy Pledge**

**1\. General Statement:**

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. This privacy statement explains our policies and practices regarding online customer information. It is through this disclosure that we intend to provide you with a level of comfort and confidence in how we collect, use, and safeguard personal and other information we collect or that you provide through this website, and how you can contact us if you have any questions or concerns. It is our sincere hope that by explaining our data handling practices we will develop a trusting and long-lasting relationship with you. By using the site, you agree to the terms of this privacy statement.

**2\. Information About Our Organization and Website:**

This Privacy Statement applies to <http://social.ford.com/> and to certain pages on this site that are linked/overlayed on certain Ford social media sites such as Facebook pages (which may appear as apps) and link to or reference this Privacy Statement (herein referenced as “social.ford.com,” “site,” or “website”). social.ford.com is owned by Ford Motor Company, Marketing, Sales and Service Division, 16800 Executive Plaza Drive, Dearborn, MI 48126.

The business purpose of this website is to provide: (1) visitors with Ford’s perspective on news and current events relevant to Ford Motor Company, its employees and its customers; (2) samples of what others are saying about Ford Motor Company, and its products; and (3) customers with a place to post their opinions, stories, and photos, and to obtain, share and download badges.

**3\. Personally Identifiable Information We Collect From You:**

When you visit social.ford.com we will not collect any personal information about you unless you provide it to us voluntarily. Personal data includes information that is particular to you such as name, street address, telephone number, and email address. If you opt not to provide us with personal information you can still access our website, however you may be unable to join Ford Social, create log in credentials, select certain badges, participate in certain promotions, set preferences to automatically share what you have read, videos watched or photo’s viewed on Facebook, **** or receive product information.

Some site functionalities require you to provide your personal information such as when you create a profile and log in credentials, provide comments or upload photos. Instead of having to type in all of your personal information, some of these functionalities may allow you to utilize third-party authentication tools such as Facebook, Twitter, and Google to populate certain fields. In addition, certain pages of this website may appear as overlays on social media sites (e.g., Facebook, Google+ and others). This will allow for integration with those sites, some of which may require you to allow Ford to access your personal information or other information you have made public. By authenticating through one of the social media options or utilizing available applications overlayed on and integrated with social media sites, you allow us to receive your personal and other information that is accessible. For the tool you chose to utilize, we encourage you to review the tool provider’s privacy policy and any terms and conditions.

Our primary goal in collecting personal information from you when you visit social.ford.com is to provide you the functionality and services that you need to have a meaningful and customized experience while using the site features.

This site may use session or persistent “cookies” to collect personally identifiable information in order to verify log in credentials. An explanation for each of these items and how they work is included in Section 7 – Methods to Collect Information.

Email addresses collected at the point of the Tell-a-Friend email tools will be used solely for the purpose of forwarding to your intended recipient.

See Section 12 regarding links to third-party sites, including widgets.

Please keep in mind that if you disclose personally identifiable information or other sensitive data through social.ford.com chat room, message board, or other public online forums, this information may be collected and used by others.

**4\. How We Use the Personally Identifiable Information We Collect:**

_Personally identifiable information_ collected on social.ford.com may be used to:

  * Fulfill a site user request ((e.g., to publish your story on thefordstory.com, brochure fulfillment, lead generation, send marketing or promotional materials including emails or other information)
  * Respond to your comments or requests for information
  * Meet a request for or to develop new products or services
  * Make the user experience more customer friendly
  * Contact you if necessary in the course of processing or shipping an order for products or services
  * Generate site analytics that improve our site layout, content, product offerings and services
  * Compile user data that is stored in our corporate database and may be used for marketing and other purposes
  * Match personal data collected here with data about you that we collect through other sources
  * Comply with legal requirements

**5** _._ **Other (Non-Personally Identifiable) Information We Collect From Site Visitors:**

social.ford.com collects other information, non-personally identifiable information from site visitors. This means that we do not track these items on an individual basis that identifies the site visitor, but rather gather and collect this information on an aggregate [or anonymous] basis that includes all site visitors. Non-personal information includes tracking the site pages that are visited or the amount of time spent on our site.

Our primary goal in collecting aggregate information from you is to be able to perform site metrics that allow us to improve the functionality of the website. We need to collect aggregate information in order to track page visits and peak site usage times, and to perform site clickthrough analysis and site layout re-design.

If you visit this site using a mobile device, we collect additional non-personal information which may include the type/model of the mobile device viewing the site, the mobile device’s service provider and operating system.

We may use session and persistent “cookies,” session logs, spotlight ads/web beacons/GIF/pixel tags, banner ads or links, and third-party click tracking analytics tools (such as DART, Omniture tags, DoubleClick, Efficient Frontier, and Google Analytics) to collect aggregate or other non-personally identifiable information about site visitors. An explanation for each of these items and how they work is included in Section 7 – Methods to Collect Information.

**6\. How We Use the Aggregate or Non-Personally Identifiable Information We Collect:**

Non-Personally identifiable information collected on social.ford.com may be used to:

  * Compile aggregate and statistical data to help in website design and to identify popular features
  * Measure site activity to allow us to update our site to better meet user wants and needs
  * Make the user experience more customer friendly

social.ford.com utilizes non-personal data for the purpose of performing analytics on the user’s experience while visiting this site. This analysis:

  * Is performed on an aggregate level and does not identify you or your information personally
  * May involve the use of a third-party vendor acting on behalf of social.ford.com
  * Is performed in order to improve our website and the user experience
  * May include the use of session and/or persistent cookies to track user movement across this and other Ford Motor Company websites or to track other events within or across this and other Ford Motor Company websites
  * Third-party vendors with which Ford has entered into contracts to perform site analytics and which are provided aggregate information covered by this privacy statement are to use that information only to perform those services, and they may not share or resell this information

**7\. Methods to Collect Information:**

A “cookie” is a small text file that helps us in many ways to make your visit to our website more enjoyable and meaningful to you. For example, cookies avoid you having to log in every time you come back to one of our websites. They also allow us to tailor a website or advertisement to better match your interests and preferences. There are a couple different types of cookies.

A “session” cookie is stored only in your computer’s working memory (RAM) and only lasts for your browsing session. When you close all your browser’s windows, or when you shut down your computer, the session cookie disappears forever.

A “persistent” cookie is stored on your computer’s hard drive until a specified date, which could be tomorrow, next week, or 10 years from now. Persistent cookies stay on your computer until either a) they expire, b) they are overwritten with newer cookies, or c) you manually remove them. Most browsers can be configured not to accept cookies, however, this may prevent you from having access to some site functions or features.

This site may use third-party click tracking analytics tools (such as DART, Omniture tags, DoubleClick, Efficient Frontier, and Google Analytics) to capture clickthrough statistics.

social.ford.com may use spotlight ads/web beacons/GIF/pixel tags which are site instrumentation tools that help us to determine, for instance, whether a page has been viewed or not and, if so, how many times. Emails or electronic newsletters we send may use tools (e.g., pixel tags or web beacons) to gather email metrics and information to improve the reader’s experience such as how many of the emails are opened, if they were printed or forwarded, the type of device (e.g., mobile or PC) from which they were opened, and the city, state, and county associated with the applicable IP address. In general, any electronic image viewed as part of a webpage, including an ad banner, can act as a web beacon.

When you visit our website the server housing the pages automatically generates a “session log.” We use session logs to help us determine how people travel through our site. In this way, we can structure our pages so that the information most frequently visited is easier to find. By tracking page visits, we can also determine if the information we’re providing is being used. The only data gathered is the Internet Protocol (IP) address from which you came (which contains no personal information), the website that referred you, the pages you visited and the date and time of those visits. ****

Users may be directed to social.ford.com via banner ads, site links or QR codes. Ads, site links or QR codes that are placed by social.ford.com use cookies or web beacons to deliver metrics on the effectiveness of the ads, links or QR codes. They do not collect personal information from the user.

If you visit this site with an open ID, you may integrate with third-party social media sites, and social.ford.com may track on an aggregate level the number of visits to this site with an open ID, the number of items “liked” on this site, or items on this site that you choose to share with a third-party social media site.

Interest-Based/Online Behavioral Advertising. On some pages of our site we may allow third-party advertising partners to set web tracking tools (e.g., cookies and web beacons) to collect anonymous, non-personally identifiable information regarding your activities on those pages (e.g., your IP address, page(s) visited, time of day). We may also share such information we have collected with third-party advertising partners. These advertising partners may use this information (and similar information collected from other websites) for purposes of delivering future targeted advertisements to you when you visit other (non-Ford) sites within their networks. This practice is commonly referred to as “interest-based advertising” or “online behavioral advertising.”

Pages of our website that collect information that may be used by such advertising partners for interest-based advertising purposes are identified by a link to AdChoices on the page.

Opting out (site pages).  If you do not want your browsing while on such pages to be used for interest-based advertising purposes, you may click on the AdChoices link to opt-out of such uses by the listed advertising partner(s). Even if you opt-out through this service, we may still collect non-personally identifiable information regarding your site activities and use it for non-interest-based advertising purposes as described in this privacy statement.

Opting out (advertisements). **** Advertisements on third-party sites that contain the AdChoices link and that link to this privacy statement may have been directed to you based on anonymous, non-personally identifiable information collected by advertising partners over time and across websites. These advertisements provide a mechanism to opt-out of the advertising partners’ use of this information for interest-based advertising purposes. Even if you opt-out through this service, we may still collect and use information from the advertisements for non-interest based advertising purposes, such as to determine the effectiveness of the advertisements.

Opt-out Compliance Service. This site and advertisements on third-party sites that link to this privacy statement use the Evidon assurance service to comply with the cross-industry Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising managed by the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) ([http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/)). When you opt-out on site pages or through such advertisements, Evidon conveys your opt-out election(s) to the applicable advertising partner(s), which then know to place a cookie on your specific computer and browser (and only the specific computer and browser from which you opt out) indicating that you have opted out. If you clear your browser cookies and wish to remain opted out of interest-based advertising, you must opt-out again. The list of our advertising partners may be updated from time to time. To opt-out of internet-based advertising by all DAA-participating companies, visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.

**8\. Sharing Your Information:**

social.ford.com does not share, sell, or rent personally identifiable information with independent companies for their own use without providing you a choice.

Personal information that you provide to us in the course of using our site features or requesting a product or service through this website may be gathered and stored in one or more of our corporate databases and be used for purposes of contacting you for things like promotional offers, marketing programs, or other communications from this website or other Ford Motor Company programs and services.

We may share personal information that we collect about you with other companies within the Ford Motor Company family of companies or subsidiaries. Our “family of companies” is the group of companies related to us by common control or ownership. We share information within this “family” as a normal part of conducting business and offering products and services to our customers.

Personal information that you provide to social.ford.com may be shared with our authorized dealers. This is necessary, such as, in order as to honor your request for a price quote on a vehicle or in order to provide a dealer with information for purposes of contacting you in their regular course of business. The dealer is not restricted by social.ford.com in their use of your data.

Vendors, contractors or partners of social.ford.com who have access to your personal information in connection with providing services for social.ford.com are required to keep the information confidential and are not permitted to use this information for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for social.ford.com.

Site metrics for social.ford.com may be shared with other Ford Motor Company websites or subsidiaries or affiliates. The information shared will be aggregate data and will not include any of your personally identifiable information.

social.ford.com will disclose your personal information, without notice, if (1) in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Ford Motor Company, its affiliates or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Ford Motor Company, its affiliates or this site; or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of Ford Motor Company or affiliate personnel, users of their websites, or the public; or (2) if required to do so by law.

Contest or sweepstakes entrants only: If you are providing personally identifiable information in connection with a contest or sweepstakes through this website, and if you are selected as a winner, we may include your personally identifiable information in a publicly available winner’s list. See the applicable contest or sweepstakes rules.

**9\. Access To and Control Over the Use of Your Information:**

To correct or update your personal information contact us at:

Telephone  
800-392-3673  
800-232-5952 (TDD for the hearing impaired)

Available 8:00 am – 5:00 pm local time  
Monday – Friday

Mailing Address  
Ford Motor Company  
Customer Relationship Center  
P.O. Box 6248  
Dearborn, MI 48126

so that we may be able to process your changes. social.ford.com will use reasonable efforts to correct any factual inaccuracies in your information.

The scope of access available for this request is for information stored in the database that holds the data for social.ford.com. Any personal information that has been collected from you on other Company websites will not be accessible or changeable through the processing of this request.

**10\. Security of Your Information:**

Safeguarding information of visitors to our website is important to us. We use systems, policies and procedures to maintain accuracy of information and to protect information from loss, misuse or alteration.

When you send personal information, such as email address or telephone numbers, to social.ford.com we use “Secure Socket Layers” or SSL to protect your data. SSL is encryption technology that helps safeguard your personal information against misuse by unauthorized individuals.

Vendors, contractors or partners of social.ford.com who have access to your personal information in connection with providing services for social.ford.com are required to keep the information confidential.

Vendors are not permitted to use this information for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for social.ford.com.

**11\. Processing of Personal Data:**

By visiting this site and by providing your personally identifiable information to us, you understand and consent to the collection, use, processing, transfer, and disclosure of your personally identifiable and

non-personally identifiable information globally — including to the United States – in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Therefore, by visiting this site and by providing such information, you consent to the transfer of such information across country borders, and to the use, processing, and disclosure of such information in global locations. Your consent shall be deemed to include your consent to transfer of the personally identifiable or non-personally identifiable information to locations that may have different levels of privacy protection than in your own country.

**12\. Links to Other Sites:**

social.ford.com provides links to other websites. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of all sites that you visit, including those whose links are provided so that you can understand how those sites collect, use and share your information. social.ford.com is not responsible for the privacy statements, content or data handling practices on other websites.

If you use available mapping functionality on this website, you agree to be bound by the mapping service’s terms and conditions/privacy policy. In addition, if you are on an associated mobile site and the GPS feature on the mobile phone is turned on (if it has such capability), your GPS data may be utilized by the mapping service to determine your location in order to fulfill your request for location services.

If you choose to utilize the ShareThis widget to share content on this website with your friends, please note that ShareThis is an independent third party and is not a vendor, contractor or partner of social.ford.com. All information (personally identifiable or aggregate) that is collected by the ShareThis widget is collected by ShareThis and is subject to the ShareThis Privacy Policy and not the social.ford.com Privacy Statement.

**13\. Children’s Privacy:**

social.ford.com does not knowingly intend to collect personal information from children under 13 years of age.

If a child has provided us with personal information a parent or guardian of that child may contact us at the phone number or mailing address listed in section 14 if they want this information deleted from our records. We will then make reasonable efforts to delete the child’s information from the database that stores information for social.ford.com.

**14\. Contacting Us:**

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about this online privacy statement for social.ford.com, social.ford.com privacy practices, or have any questions regarding the contents of this website please contact us at:

Telephone  
800-392-3673  
800-232-5952 (TDD for the hearing impaired)

Available 8:00 am – 5:00 pm local time  
Monday – Friday

Mailing Address  
Ford Motor Company  
Customer Relationship Center  
P.O. Box 6248  
Dearborn, MI 48126

social.ford.com is committed to working with consumers to obtain a fair and rapid resolution of any complaints or disputes about privacy and the handling of your data. social.ford.com will be happy to respond to your questions and comments.

**15\. Privacy Statement Effective Date and Revision Days:**

Occasionally we may update the privacy statement for social.ford.com in order to reflect any changes to the website or our privacy practices. If we update this statement, the new statement will be posted to the website ten (10) days prior to the changes taking effect.

The effective date of this privacy statement is May 1, 2013.  

**1.   General Statement:**

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it.  This privacy statement explains our policies and practices regarding online customer information.  It is through this disclosure that we intend to provide you with a level of comfort and confidence in how we collect, use, and safeguard personal and other information we collect or that you provide through this website, and how you can contact us if you have any questions or concerns.  It is our sincere hope that by explaining our data handling practices we will develop a trusting and long-lasting relationship with you.  By using the site, you agree to the terms of this privacy statement.

**2.   Information About Our Organization and Website and General Data Collection Practices:**

This Privacy Statement applies to <http://social.ford.com/> and to certain pages on this site that are linked/overlayed on certain Ford social media sites such as Facebook pages (which may appear as apps) and link to or reference this Privacy Statement (herein referenced as “social.ford.com,” “site,” or “website”).  social.ford.com is owned by Ford Motor Company, Marketing, Sales and Service Division, 16800 Executive Plaza Drive, Dearborn, MI 48126.

The business purpose of this website is to provide: (1) visitors with Ford’s perspective on news and current events relevant to Ford Motor Company, its employees and its customers; (2) samples of what others are saying about Ford Motor Company, and its products; and (3) customers with a place to post their opinions, stories, and photos, and to obtain, share and download badges.

**When you visit this site, other parties such as third-party advertising partners and analytics providers may collect information about your online activity over time and across websites. This information may include identifiers that may permit those parties to serve tailored ads to your device.   For more information about third-party advertising partners’ collection and use of such data for interest-based advertising purposes (and opting out of such use), see “Interest-Based Online/Behavioral Advertising” below. **

**Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret web browser-based “Do Not Track” (“DNT”) signals other than cookies, Ford Motor Company does not currently respond to undefined “DNT” signals to its US websites.**

**Most browsers can be configured not to accept cookies, however, this may prevent you from having access to some functions or services on our sites.**

**3.   Personally Identifiable Information We Collect From You:**

When you visit social.ford.com we will not collect any personally identifiable information about you unless you provide it to us voluntarily.  For purposes of this Privacy Statement “personally identifiable information” is information that identifies you as an individual, for example your name, street address, telephone number, and email address.  If you opt not to provide us with personally identifiable information you can still access our website, however you may be unable to join Ford Social, create log in credentials, select certain badges, participate in certain promotions, set preferences to automatically share what you have read, videos watched or photo’s viewed on Facebook, **** or receive product information.

Some site functionalities require you to provide your personally identifiable information such as when you create a profile and log in credentials, provide comments or upload photos.  Instead of having to type in all of your personally identifiable information, some of these functionalities may allow you to utilize third-party authentication tools such as Facebook, Twitter, and Google to populate certain fields.  In addition, certain pages of this website may appear as overlays on social media sites (e.g., Facebook, Google+ and others). This will allow for integration with those sites, some of which may require you to allow Ford to access your personally identifiable information or other information you have made public. By authenticating through one of the social media options or utilizing available applications overlayed on and integrated with social media sites, you allow us to receive your information that is accessible.  For the tool you chose to utilize, we encourage you to review the tool provider’s privacy policy and any terms and conditions.

This site may use session and persistent “cookies” to collect personally identifiable information in order to verify login credentials, and it may use a third party to deliver site functionality.  An explanation on collection methods and how they work is included in Section 7 – Methods to Collect Information.

Our primary goal in collecting personally identifiable information from you when you visit social.ford.com is to provide you the functionality and services that you need to have a meaningful and customized experience while using the site features.

Email addresses collected at the point of the Tell-a-Friend email tools will be used solely for the purpose of forwarding to your intended recipient.

See Section 12 regarding links to third-party sites, including widgets.

Please keep in mind that if you disclose personally identifiable information or other sensitive data through social.ford.com chat room, message board, or other public online forums, this information may be collected and used by others.

**4.   How We Use the Personally Identifiable Information We Collect:**

_Personally identifiable information_ collected on social.ford.com may be used to:

  * Fulfill a site user request ((e.g., to publish your story on thefordstory.com, brochure fulfillment, lead generation, send marketing or promotional materials including emails or other information)
  * Respond to your comments or requests for information
  * Meet a request for or to develop new products or services
  * Make the user experience more customer friendly
  * Contact you if necessary in the course of processing or shipping an order for products or services
  * Generate site analytics that improve our site layout, content, product offerings and services
  * Compile user data that is stored in our corporate database and may be used for marketing and other purposes
  * Match personal data collected here with data about you that we collect through other sources
  * Comply with legal requirements

**5** _._ **Other (Non-Personally Identifiable) Information We Collect From Site Visitors:**

social.ford.com collects other “non-personally identifiable information” from site visitors.  This means that we do not track these items on an individual basis that identifies the site visitor, but rather gather and collect this information on an aggregate [or anonymous] basis that includes all site visitors.  Non-personally identifiable information includes tracking the site pages that are visited or the amount of time spent on our site.

Our primary goal in collecting non-personally identifiable information from you is to be able to perform site metrics that allow us to improve the functionality of the website.

If you visit this site using a mobile device, we collect additional non-personally identifiable information which may include the type/model of the mobile device viewing the site, the mobile device’s service provider and operating system.

We may use session and persistent “cookies,” session logs, spotlight ads/web beacons/GIF/pixel tags, banner ads or links, and third-party click tracking analytics tools (such as Adobe, DoubleClick, Efficient Frontier, and Google Analytics) to collect aggregate or other non-personally identifiable information about site visitors.  An explanation on collection methods and how they work is included in Section 7 – Methods to Collect Information.

**6.   How We Use the Aggregate or Non-Personally Identifiable Information We Collect:**

Non-Personally identifiable information collected on social.ford.com may be used to:

  * Compile aggregate and statistical data to help in website design and to identify popular features
  * Measure site activity to allow us to update our site to better meet user wants and needs
  * Make the user experience more customer friendly

social.ford.com utilizes non-personally identifiable information for the purpose of performing analytics on the user’s experience while visiting this site. This analysis:

  * Is performed on an aggregate level and does not identify you or your information personally
  * May involve the use of a third-party vendor acting on behalf of social.ford.com
  * Is performed in order to improve our website and the user experience
  * May include the use of session and/or persistent cookies to track user movement across this and other Ford Motor Company websites or to track other events within or across this and other Ford Motor Company websites
  * Third-party vendors with which Ford has entered into contracts to perform site analytics and which are provided aggregate information covered by this privacy statement are to use that information only to perform those services, and they may not share or resell this information

**7.   Methods to Collect Information:**

A “cookie” is a small text file that helps us in many ways to make your visit to our website more enjoyable and meaningful to you. For example, cookies avoid you having to log in every time you come back to one of our websites. They also allow us to tailor a website or advertisement to better match your interests and preferences.  There are a couple different types of cookies.

A “session” cookie is stored only in your computer’s working memory (RAM) and only lasts for your browsing session. When you close all your browser’s windows, or when you shut down your computer, the session cookie disappears forever.

A “persistent” cookie is stored on your computer’s hard drive until a specified date, which could be tomorrow, next week, or 10 years from now. Persistent cookies stay on your computer until either a) they expire, b) they are overwritten with newer cookies, or c) you manually remove them.  Most browsers can be configured not to accept cookies, however, this may prevent you from having access to some site functions or features.

This site may use third-party click tracking analytics tools (such as Adobe and Google Analytics) to capture clickthrough statistics.

social.ford.com may use spotlight ads/web beacons/GIF/pixel tags which are site instrumentation tools that help us to determine, for instance, whether a page has been viewed or not and, if so, how many times.  Emails or electronic newsletters we send may use tools (e.g., pixel tags or web beacons) to gather email metrics and information to improve the reader’s experience such as how many of the emails are opened, if they were printed or forwarded, the type of device (e.g., mobile or PC) from which they were opened, and the city, state, and county associated with the applicable IP address.  In general, any electronic image viewed as part of a webpage, including an ad banner, can act as a web beacon.

When you visit our website the server housing the pages automatically generates a “session log.”  We use session logs to help us determine how people travel through our site. In this way, we can structure our pages so that the information most frequently visited is easier to find. By tracking page visits, we can also determine if the information we’re providing is being used.  The only data gathered is the Internet Protocol (IP) address from which you came (which contains no personally identifiable information), the website that referred you, the pages you visited and the date and time of those visits. ****

Users may be directed to social.ford.com via banner ads, site links or QR codes.  Ads, site links or QR codes that are placed by social.ford.com use cookies or web beacons to deliver metrics on the effectiveness of the ads, links or QR codes.  They do not collect personally identifiable information from the user.

If you visit this site with an open ID, you may integrate with third-party social media sites, and social.ford.com may track on an aggregate level the number of visits to this site with an open ID, the number of items “liked” on this site, or items on this site that you choose to share with a third-party social media site.

Interest-Based/Online Behavioral Advertising. On some pages of our site we may allow third-party advertising partners to set web tracking tools (e.g., cookies and web beacons) to collect anonymous, non-personally identifiable information regarding your activities on those pages (e.g., your IP address, page(s) visited, time of day).  We may also share such information we have collected with third-party advertising partners.  These advertising partners may use this information (and similar information collected from other websites) for purposes of delivering future targeted advertisements to you when you visit other (non-Ford) sites within their networks.  This practice is commonly referred to as “interest-based advertising” or “online behavioral advertising.”

Pages of our website that collect information that may be used by such advertising partners for interest-based advertising purposes are identified by a link to AdChoices on the page.

Opting out (site pages).  If you do not want your browsing while on such pages to be used for interest-based advertising purposes, you may click on the AdChoices link to opt-out of such uses by the listed advertising partner(s).  Even if you opt-out through this service, we may still collect non-personally identifiable information regarding your site activities and use it for non-interest-based advertising purposes as described in this privacy statement.

Opting out (advertisements). **** Advertisements on third-party sites that contain the AdChoices link and that link to this privacy statement may have been directed to you based on anonymous, non-personally identifiable information collected by advertising partners over time and across websites.  These advertisements provide a mechanism to opt-out of the advertising partners’ use of this information for interest-based advertising purposes.  Even if you opt-out through this service, we may still collect and use information from the advertisements for non-interest based advertising purposes, such as to determine the effectiveness of the advertisements.

Opt-out Compliance Service.  This site and advertisements on third-party sites that link to this privacy statement use the Evidon assurance service to comply with the cross-industry Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising managed by the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) ([http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/)).  When you opt-out on site pages or through such advertisements, Evidon conveys your opt-out election(s) to the applicable advertising partner(s), which then know to place a cookie on your specific computer and browser (and only the specific computer and browser from which you opt out) indicating that you have opted out. If you clear your browser cookies and wish to remain opted out of interest-based advertising, you must opt-out again.  The list of our advertising partners may be updated from time to time.  To opt-out of internet-based advertising by all DAA-participating companies, visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.

**8.   Sharing Your Information:**

social.ford.com does not share, sell, or rent personally identifiable information with independent companies for their own use without providing you a choice.

Personally identifiable information that you provide to us in the course of using our site features or requesting a product or service through this website may be gathered and stored in one or more of our corporate databases and be used for purposes of contacting you for things like promotional offers, marketing programs, or other communications from this website or other Ford Motor Company programs and services.

We may share personally identifiable information that we collect about you with other companies within the Ford Motor Company family of companies or subsidiaries.  Our “family of companies” is the group of companies related to us by common control or ownership.  We share information within this “family” as a normal part of conducting business and offering products and services to our customers.

Personally identifiable information that you provide to social.ford.com may be shared with our authorized dealers.  This is necessary, such as, in order as to honor your request for a price quote on a vehicle or in order to provide a dealer with information for purposes of contacting you in their regular course of business.  The dealer is not restricted by social.ford.com in their use of your data.

Vendors, contractors or partners of social.ford.com who have access to your personally identifiable information in connection with providing services for social.ford.com are required to keep the information confidential and are not permitted to use this information for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for social.ford.com.

Site metrics for social.ford.com may be shared with other Ford Motor Company websites or subsidiaries or affiliates.  The information shared will be aggregate data and will not include any of your personally identifiable information.

social.ford.com will disclose your personally identifiable information, without notice, if (1) in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Ford Motor Company, its affiliates or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Ford Motor Company, its affiliates or this site; or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of Ford Motor Company or affiliate personnel, users of their websites, or the public; or (2) if required to do so by law.

Contest or sweepstakes entrants only:  If you are providing personally identifiable information in connection with a contest or sweepstakes through this website, and if you are selected as a winner, we may include your personally identifiable information in a publicly available winner’s list.  See the applicable contest or sweepstakes rules.

**9.   Access To and Control Over the Use of Your Personally Identifiable Information:**

To correct or update your personally identifiable information contact us at:

Telephone  
800-392-3673  
800-232-5952 (TDD for the hearing impaired)

Available 8:00 am – 5:00 pm EST  
Monday – Friday

Mailing Address  
Ford Motor Company  
Customer Relationship Center  
P.O. Box 6248  
Dearborn, MI 48126

You will be asked for name and address so that we may be able to process your changes.  social.ford.com will use reasonable efforts to correct any factual inaccuracies in your information.

The scope of access available for this request is for information stored in the database that holds the data for social.ford.com.  Any personally identifiable information that has been collected from you on other Company websites will not be accessible or changeable through the processing of this request.

**10.   Security of Your Information:**

Safeguarding information of visitors to our website is important to us.  We use systems, policies and procedures to maintain accuracy of information and to protect information from loss, misuse or alteration.

When you send personally identifiable information, such as email address or telephone numbers, to social.ford.com we use “Secure Socket Layers” or SSL to protect your data.  SSL is encryption technology that helps safeguard your personally identifiable information against misuse by unauthorized individuals.

Vendors, contractors or partners of social.ford.com who have access to your personally identifiable information in connection with providing services for social.ford.com are required to keep the information confidential.

**11.   Consent to Processing:**

By visiting this site and by providing your personally identifiable information to us, you understand and consent to the collection, use, processing, transfer, and disclosure of your personally identifiable and

non-personally identifiable information globally — including to the United States – in accordance with this Privacy Statement.  Therefore, by visiting this site and by providing such information, you consent to the transfer of such information across country borders, and to the use, processing, and disclosure of such information in global locations.  Your consent shall be deemed to include your consent to transfer of the personally identifiable or non-personally identifiable information to locations that may have different levels of privacy protection than in your own country.

**12.   Links to Other Sites:**

social.ford.com provides links to other websites.  We encourage you to review the privacy statements of all sites that you visit, including those whose links are provided so that you can understand how those sites collect, use and share your information.  social.ford.com is not responsible for the privacy statements, content or data handling practices on other websites.

If you use available mapping functionality on this website, you agree to be bound by the mapping service’s terms and conditions/privacy policy.  In addition, if you are on an associated mobile site and the GPS feature on the mobile phone is turned on (if it has such capability), your GPS data may be utilized by the mapping service to determine your location in order to fulfill your request for location services.

If you choose to utilize the ShareThis widget to share content on this website with your friends, please note that ShareThis is an independent third party and is not a vendor, contractor or partner of social.ford.com.  All information (personally identifiable or aggregate) that is collected by the ShareThis widget is collected by ShareThis and is subject to the ShareThis Privacy Policy and not the social.ford.com Privacy Statement.

**13.   Children’s Privacy:**

social.ford.com does not knowingly intend to collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age.

If a child has provided us with personally identifiable information a parent or guardian of that child may contact us at the phone number or mailing address listed in section 14 if they want this information deleted from our records.  We will then make reasonable efforts to delete the child’s information from the database that stores information for social.ford.com.

**14.   Contacting Us:**

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about this online privacy statement for social.ford.com, social.ford.com privacy practices, or have any questions regarding the contents of this website please contact us at:

Telephone  
800-392-3673  
800-232-5952 (TDD for the hearing impaired)

Available 8:00 am – 5:00 pm EST  
Monday – Friday

Mailing Address  
Ford Motor Company  
Customer Relationship Center  
P.O. Box 6248  
Dearborn, MI 48126

social.ford.com is committed to working with consumers to obtain a fair and rapid resolution of any complaints or disputes about privacy and the handling of your data.  social.ford.com will be happy to respond to your questions and comments.

**15.   Privacy Statement Effective Date and Revision Days:**

Occasionally we may update the privacy statement for social.ford.com in order to reflect any changes to the website or our privacy practices.  If we update this statement, the new statement will be posted to the website ten (10) days prior to the changes taking effect.

The effective date of this privacy statement is January 1, 2014.
